In this clip we're going to make a pattern for our eye mask.
I already have a eye mask it's just a plain kind of boring one that I bought at a eye mask store.
So I'm just going to use this as a template but if you don't have a sleeping mask basically you want something that's an oval shape about 6" wide.
You want a place cut out for your nose so you basically make a long oval and then we're going to cut out for the nose.
So I'm just going to bring this to my paper and then I'm going to go ahead and trace it.
You just go ahead and trace it we're going to lift up the little nose guard part and come back down.
This doesn't has to be exact cause we're going to clean it up when we cut it out.
I actually want mine to come down a little further so I'm just going to go ahead and free hand it.
What you do when you are actually free handing something is you go ahead and just fold it in half and then we'll cut it out so the other side is the exact same shape.
Always remember when you are making patterns or cutting out patterns to have a separate scissors you can use just for paper.
Cause you don't want to use the fabric scissors.
We'll go ahead and see this is a little bit to straight so we're going to go ahead and clean that line up just a little.
Once you have your paper pattern we're ready to transfer this onto our fabric and cut it out.